Dammit!
Everyone on the team...
knows how you must feel.
So I think...
...that's exactly why Nanao decided
to ask you that question... in front of all of us.
And in that moment, you answered clearly.
It psyched me up. Seeing your bravery.
Y-yeah.
Ahiru no Sora
Nice, Chucky!
VOW
Defense! Defense! Defense! Defense!
Shit, they just won't let up.
Only 3 more minutes...
We're not losing the lead now!
Keep your heads in the game!
The first match of the day
is turning out to be a real spectacle.
If memory serves, neither of these schools
even entered the tourney last year.
What a shame! They've both
got such amazing players.
I hope this is a sign
that more high schoolers
are taking an interest in
the game of basketball.
He's boxing me out!
Koji and I were the only
members in our freshmen year.
Playing in a game like this was a pipe dream.
Basketball
Team
The year after that, we still
couldn't get up to 5 members.
Basketball
Team
And now our first go at the inter-high tourney...
is also our last!
Did he foul...?
No, they're not calling it.
I let him get by!
We can't afford to waste all our stamina
in this very first game!
Not on my watch!
Loose ball!
A three-pointer!
Rebound!
It went in!
Now we're ahead by 4!
Simply wonderful, Roku!
Thanks.
Okay, just a bit more!
Let's go into the second
half with a solid lead!
Right!
We WILL win this!
Defense! Defense! Defense! Defense!
The first half is just about to end.
We have to avoid letting them
get a huge lead here at the very least.
That means no screw ups.
We have to keep up with them no matter what!
Until Chiaki comes back into the game!
The qualities that a good
point guard needs most?
That's simple, a manly attitude
and chiseled good looks.
But Chiaki... you don't have any of that.
If I have to be real,
then an eye for opportunity is essential.
Particularly when it comes to hot babes.
You always fail 'cuz you try
to memorize them one-by-one.
You'll never be a good point guard
unless you learn to look at the bigger picture.
Channel your five senses.
Your whole team is aiming for the basket.
Nice pass!
That pass got them into a good spot!
That guy has some smooth moves!
It's a hook! Get on the
side with the ball, Yukio!
LIGHT
I guess he really does know his shit.
GREASED
LIGHTNING
Pretty good. Is this how
Kuzu High always plays?
Dunno. This is the first year
they've ever participated.
It's a good thing we came to check them out.
Nice assist!
Right back at you. Great pass, Kurumatani.
You missed me making a cut
for the basket three times.
You gotta pay more attention.
Sorry.
He sure likes to gets on everybody's case,
but I have to admit he plays the game well.
But honestly, the more I look at it,
the weirder his hair gets.
Huh? Did you say something?
That's our freshmen trio.
They're pretty damn impressive.
All right! Time to totally shut them down!
Bring the pain!
I screwed up...!
Holding! White #6!
That damn attention whore.
I'll make him pay for this.
He made me look like a complete fool
in front of everyone.
And the worst part is...
...Nao saw every second of it!
He missed the second one!
Whoa! Nice rebound!
We're pretty much invincible under the basket
now thanks to Momoharu and Mokichi!
I think we're really starting
to turn this around!
We can probably hold our own
for a while even without Chiaki!
Don't ya think so, Nao?
Huh? Oh, I suppose so.
Sweet! I'm getting psyched up now!
Damn. It won't go in!
Counter!
That one's gonna hurt bad.
Right after things started going their way.
Hey, Mokichi.
You okay?
Oh, yeah. I'm fine.
I see... I hadn't noticed until now,
but since they have to run between
the very ends of the court
the center has the most strenuous job of all.
I've gotta switch up the
rhythm of our offense,
and spread out the burden
among us more equally.
We've been playing almost exclusively
in the post for a while now.
Is that little idiot trying to kill me?!
Holy cow! Did you see that pass just now?
He chucked it from behind
the half court line!
Our resident shorty is
starting to find his groove!
Ain't that right, Chiaki?
Huh?
Chiaki...?
That's the end of the first half!
It's down to a 2 point game.
Shinjo worked hard to defend their lead.
That last pass was really incredible though.
Man, this game is super high
level. Both teams are good.
It seems they were evenly matched
for the entire first half.
Well, I'm not surprised.
The second half will test
more than skill, the team
with the better stamina and
concentration will cinch it.
This is where they're going to have
to set themselves apart.
Alrighty then. It's about time for us
to start warming up. Let's move!
Roger that.
He's nothing at all like
when we played before.
I can tell that he really
practiced his ass off.
I'm looking forward to our rematch.
Huh? Where'd Chiaki and Nanao go?
Yeah, about that... Chiaki just up and vanished
a couple of minutes ago.
So Nao had to leave to go and check on him.
Where do you think he got off to?
Dunno.
Must be taking a shit or something.
I'm sure he'll be back soon.
We have more important things
to focus on right now.
Everybody needs to rest up and recover
what stamina they can before the second half starts.
Goddammit... I totally spaced
on how rotten his attitude can get!
The hell are you doing, man?!
We're still in the middle of a game!
I mean, there's no point if we can't win.
I don't wanna keep playing
when we look so uncool.
Don't tell me... that bastard did it again?!
What's the matter, Captain?
You look like you're gonna puke.
HURRY!
Get the lead out, Kato! We gotta speed it up!
I'm telling you, we don't have to rush
because it's only halftime!
Hurry!
But I... want to spend as much time
in Nao's presence as possible.
Hold up a sec!
Wait, don't pull!
WHAT THE HELL, MAN?!
Look... over there.
Huh?
That's gotta be somebody else.
There's no way he'd be here.
But he's wearing the
uniform and everything...
He's coming this way!
Why is he chasing us?!
And why the hell is the
cashier following after him?!
Premium Popsicle Soda Flavor
Total: 5 Items
Yen
Th-that'll be 324 yen, please.
Don't eat popsicles you that can't pay for, dammit!
Especially not FIVE of them!
And this, too.
Just put the magazine back!
3 fouls in the first half?
Damn, that's gotta be rough.
I actually got 4 in our game today,
so it's a big problem for me, too.
I don't care about the peanut gallery,
but Nao is the one person I
never want to see me as uncool.
Huh?
MIYUKI OVERPASS
Did Nao actually say that to you?
That you were "uncool"?
I figured. She's not the type
to look down on people like that.
Back when I first started
and absolutely sucked,
and even when our team got wrecked
by stronger schools...
...Nao would always cheer
me on with a big smile.
To her, I always looked cool on the court.
She's never said anything different.
So don't you dare...
disrespect Nao like that!
Taro...
I guess this Suzuki dude is a
pretty decent guy after all.
Huh?
Just who the hell is Suzuki?!
Huh? Wasn't that your name?
In any case, you should
really get back there.
It's not unheard of to get a
technical foul for ditching.
Seriously?
Not to mention, any team
will struggle to play
without their point guard,
three fouls or not.
We can probably hold our own for a while
even without Chiaki!
Huh? Oh, I suppose so.
No... I'm not...
Chiaki!
Nao...
Hey, Nao! You came all this way to meet me?
My angel!
Huh? What are you doing out here Taro?!
Hey, Nao, you've got some
blood on your knee...
Oh... I tripped and fell a minute ago.
I've been worried about you.
What on Earth made you disappear like that?
She came... all the way out here to find me?
She ran herself ragged just for me?
What a relief. I had no idea
what I was going to do if I couldn't find you.
Shit. I look... drastically uncool right now.
Now listen here!
Whenever you get benched from now on...
I'm begging you, Nao. Just
please don't look at me...
Here, take this!
Use it to wipe off your sweat.
Make sure you keep your
body from getting too cold.
Everybody worked real hard out there
to make sure you wouldn't come back to a big mess.
So be sure to show your
appreciation later, okay?
Oh, I get it...
Nao's already seen it,
she's always watched us struggle to improve...
Okay! I need to get back right away
to have a meeting with the others.
But I want you to walk back slowly
so you don't get tired, Chiaki.
There's still plenty of time left!
It's just like seaweed head said...
All right!
We gotta get going too, Kato!
Wait!
What? What do you want this time?
You're going down, seaweed head.
I'll become the most important person to Nao.
Huh?! What the hell?!
In other words, I'm going to become
the best basketball player in Japan.
Huh?
I will... never lose to anyone!
Juri? What's up with this text?
How'd she get her hands on a phone?
bought a celly
r u playing now?
Jeez, she ain't even using full sentences.
was gonna come see u play
2day 4 real
was saving my monies for it
was gonna come see u play
2day 4 real
was saving my monies for it
I was gonna come see you play today for real.
I was saving my money for it.
but couldn't w8 and
bought a celly yesterday
But I couldn't wait and bought
a cellphone yesterday.
but couldn't w8
and bought a celly yesterday
so can't now.
So I can't now.
Oh great. So I'm playing second fiddle
to the fancy new cellphone.
but couldn't w8
and bought a celly yesterday
so can't now.
pls be a gr8 player
and listen to ur coach
don't cause any
problems 4 ppl.
Please be a great player
and listen to your coach.
Don't cause any problems for people.
She sounds like our mom...
do ur best.
Do your best!
Yeah. I'll do my best.
I guess this is what I get...
for quitting basketball once.
Just 5 minutes and I'm exhausted...
Hey Manager, you're in charge of drinks.
SAIJO
The water for icing injuries is in the cooler box.
So get that ready, too.
I'm beat...
We managed to stop the other team
from taking a huge lead.
But I had no idea all the anxiety and pressure
would wipe me out this much...
Please Chiaki, hurry and get back!
You hanging in there?
Madoka...?
Hey Yabuuchi.
What the hell are you doing out here?
Hey! Have a little more respect!
We came all the way here to cheer you guys on!
It's only natural for us to
come see how things pan out,
especially after all that time
we spent helping you practice.
That's for sure. If they're gonna go out,
I hope it's with a bang!
Please stop making it sound like
they're doomed to lose this match!
If you're just gonna be a
nuisance, then go the hell home.
Oh? Only 2 points behind!
You guys are putting up a fight!
Um, how about the girls' team?
We lost our game.
But it was soooo close!
Seriously, you won't believe it!
We had it down to a 1 point
game at the very end!
I can't concentrate with all
this screeching going on!
We had a chance!
It was totally down to the wire!
Here. You can have this.
We put literally everything we had into it!
For sure!
What's this supposed to be?
Brown sugar candies for a calorie boost.
You guys didn't prepare
anything like this, did you?
Oh, thank you.
Here. You all should have some.
Thanks grandma...
Too damn sweet!
You need the boost.
I hear you scored 24
points in the first half alone?
You're on fire.
You know, your face is all
sorts of beautiful, girl.
You should wear your hair up.
Don't let it go to waste.
Huh? You... you really think so?
What a god!
Do you enjoy eating sweet
candies, Shigeyoshi?
Yeah... I, uh, love them.
Great. Then I'll give you a bonus piece.
Here, Momoharu. You need one, too.
Great, thanks.
Ice Pack
I'll give you this in return.
Huh?
'Cuz your eyes are all puffy.
Oh crap! He noticed!
I knew I should've put on a pair of glasses!
Although, you should know
I was keeping it in my underwear.
Ugh! Then keep it to yourself!
Man, these candies are super tasty.
He's really got sharp eyes.
Got one for you, Sora. Here.
They went in and then stopped.
Do you... understand what that means?
We can do this! We will win!
All that energy they have
will definitely drop off in the second half!
When it comes to hidden reserves,
we have the advantage!
Don't any of you dare give up!
Think back on all of the
training that we've done!
Yes, sir!
Koji, did you notice anything we could
improve upon while you were watching?
Nope. Do you think we're struggling
'cuz our team is weak...
...or 'cuz Kuzu High is just that strong?
I was sure that we could
compete on an even level,
whether we went up against
Saijo or Shinmaruko.
And I'm not just being an arrogant jackass.
This is a damn good matchup.
I think we can get our 3 years worth of fun
right from the start.
Very true. That's a good point.
This is what we always wanted.
Ever since we were freshmen.
A match? But there's only 2 of you...
We roughed it out for 2 years
playing against middle schoolers
and training absolute novices.
We've been waiting to taste
the thrill of a close game,
where we have to fight for every point.
And right now... I am
definitely living that dream!
Kazushi. Yukio.
Did you think our practice
sessions were too hardcore?
Huh?
Why are you asking out of the blue?
They were way too hardcore! I
wanted to quit all the time.
But you weren't one of the noobs!
You guys are amazing to make it this far.
Thanks for hanging in there.
Captain, you're supposed to
save that for after the game.
Yeah, exactly! After we win it all!
Buzz off.
What a jerk!
C'mon dude, it's not like everybody
is playing for your sake.
Yeah, I know that.
I just... wanted to try saying it.
Ain't that a coincidence.
I was thinking about doing
the exact same thing.
I'm so sorry for getting back late!
Hey, Nanao! What about Chiaki?
He's okay.
Huh?
Anyways, I'm really sorry.
We don't have time for a proper meeting now.
Don't worry about it. It's not
gonna be a problem for us.
Only 3 minutes left...
Pay attention. I need all
of you to listen closely.
It's true that we were
unable to make a comeback
in the last 5 minutes of the first half.
However, there is no doubt
that we were in control of the game for that time.
So in order to keep our momentum strong,
we're going all in right from
the start of the second half.
Shigeyoshi, I want to keep you
out on the court. Is that okay?
Yeah. Of course.
If Kurumatani decides to make a fast break,
don't force yourself to keep up.
Momoharu will dash at full speed
to provide support instead.
Right.
Shigeyoshi can prepare for the event
we get a second chance.
Understood.
Hold up a sec! What about Chiaki?
He's on the bench until
the fourth quarter, dude.
Even if we put bro back on
the court, he couldn't do mu-
DEATH!
Oh crap! Kite!
I think you boys have been screwing around
a little too much lately.
And just where the hell
have you been, jackass?!
You better not have gone to stuff your face
with a damn popsicle again!
Nature called!
You can drop the scary face with me, dude.
Miss Nao.
Uh, yes?
I want off the bench. So,
please put me back in.
To assure our victory.
And... to kindle our love.
What the hell are you talking about, dumbass?
You've got three fouls, remember?!
We sure as hell can't afford to let you
get ejected in the third quart-
That's fine with me.
Huh?!
However, I'm benching you
the instant you get a fourth foul.
And then I'm not letting you back in
until the final 3 minutes.
I like what you said earlier.
I'm going to borrow it.
Shinjoooooo! Fight!
We're gonna climb our way to the top!
Don't let anything stop us!
Right!
Let's get out there. And assure our victory!
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: Bonds
Next episode: "Bonds."